Guide to the David Paul Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
David Paul papers
1945-1986
GEN MSS 820
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2
(2 boxes)
The David Paul Papers contain his writings, correspondence, printed material, and notebooks.
Paul, David, 1914-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from John Byrne on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 1995.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Writings, 1945-1985. II. Correspondence, 1960-1986.
David Paul (1914-1987)
David Paul was a British poet, playwright, essayist, novelist, and translator.
Scope and Contents
The David Paul Papers contain his writings, correspondence, printed material, and notebooks.
Authors, British -- 20th Century -- Archives; British literature -- 20th Century; Scripts (documents); Authors, English -- 20th Century; Paul, David, 1914-
- Writings, 1945-1985; Series I; 1.5; (2 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Organized into three subseries: Plays; Poems; and Other Writings
  Scope and Contents
  Series I contains writings, printed material, and notebooks by or relating to David Paul, and includes play scripts, poems, short stories, and other works.
  - Plays
    - Afternoon Girl: A Comedy for Television; Isabella: A Renaissance Portrait, undated (Box 1)
    - The Basket. Play accepted by the Royal Court [Theatre], undated (Box 1)
    - Happy Liars: A Comedy in Three Acts, undated (Box 1)
    - Poor Mrs. Machiavelli!, 1968 (Box 1)
    - Prodigal: A Play in Three Acts, undated (Box 1)
    - The Prodigal Boy or Tom the Traveler, undated (Box 1)
    - Remember Who You Are, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    - Sweeney Tom or Simply Agonistes, 1976, undated; 2 (Box 1)
    - Write Down Your Particulars, undated (Box 1)
  - Poems
    - Exercise books and notebooks containing drafts of poems, undated; 3 (Box 1)
    - Poems, undated; 3 (Box 1)
    - Cold Hands Warm Heart and Other Poems, undated (Box 1)
    - Poems. First choice for a collection, undated (Box 1)
    - Poems. First drafts and early poems, undated (Box 1)
    - Introduction (essay) and translation for Poison and Vision, undated (Box 1)
    - Translations. Poison and Vision: poems, undated; 3 (Box 1)
    - Self-portraits: poems, notebook, undated (Box 1)
    - Speech for an Inca Skull and other Poems, undated (Box 2)
    - Translations: poems, undated; 2 (Box 2)
    - Early reviews, 1947-1953 (Box 2)
    - Reviews: proofs, 1945-1948 (Box 2)
    - Reviews and The Creature in the Cave, 1947-1949, undated (Box 2)
    - Reviews and early poems, 1947-1952, undated (Box 2)
  - Other writings
    - Short stories, undated (Box 2)
    - Essays and reviews and The Bard and Co.: (New Criterion), 1963-1985 (Box 2)
    - Full Moon on Friday and other tales, undated (Box 2)
    - The Immortal Gods And Other Conjectures: prose, undated (Box 2)
    - Relativities. Pages from a Notebook: prose, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Under Uranus: A Novel, undated (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous poems, prose, reviews and proofs, undated; 2 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1960-1986; Series II; 9
  - Outgoing correspondence (carbons), 1960-1986; 6 (Box 2)
  - Contracts and correspondence with Random House and others, 1972-1974; 3 (Box 2)